# WILLIAM

■ WillWebDesigns@gmail.com

www.williamdiep.me

SF Bay Area, CA

in www.linkedin.com/in/wdiep

Full Stack Developer (Front End Focus) with a love of design who has seven years of experience in systems administration and tech support, and ten years of experience in teaching and mentoring. Recent positions include providing customercentric tier 1 and 2 support with scopes of project management and consulting services. Passion for teaching, building, and learning new technologies.

# Skills

HTML5/CSS3

SASS

JavaScript/ES6

iOuerv

Python

Templating Engines

Webpack

Gulp

Bootstrap 4

Foundation 6

Git

**MVC** Architecture

Content Management Systems

Responsive Web Design

Search Engine Optimization

Google Analytics

MailChimp

Adobe Photoshop

NodeJS

MongoDB

Digital Ocean

Amazon Web Services

Nainx

Apache

# Education

# San Jose State University

Bachelor of Science Health Science 2013 GPA 3.4/4.0

# Foothill College

Associate of Science Computer Science 2018 GPA 3.85/4.0

# Front End Developer Code Camp (Cañada College)

Enrolled in a 16-week immersive training program learning front-end programming, data structures, algorithms, & agile development

Collaborated in agile teams to plan and create websites and web apps

# **Experience**

#### theCoderSchool

**Coding Instructor** 

San Jose & Fremont, CA · Jul 2017

• Instruct and mentor 6 - 16 year olds web development, game development, and data structures and algorithms using HTML5/ CSS3, JavaScript, and Python

# Will's Web Designs

SF Bay Area, CA · May 2016 to Current

Full Stack Developer

- · Design and full stack development of responsive websites and web apps, and database architecture for small businesses
- Consult with clients, provide scope of project, proposals, and statement of work

### NASA Ames Research Center

Mountain View, CA · Jan 2013 to Jul 2013

Junior Graphic & Web Content Manager (Intern)

- · Generated, revised and, managed webpages for the Earth Science Division using HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript. Improved web usability while providing administrative support to senior team members
- Collaboratively worked in a team of four to effectively create over 25 high-quality designs of brochures, posters, and presentations using Microsoft Office Suite and Adobe Photoshop in an aggressive one-month time-frame resulting an increase of \$28K funding
- Coached four interns on a 1-1 basis on using Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Photoshop, & Adobe Illustrator increasing team efficiency by ten fold

#### GoFundMe

Redwood City, CA · Aug 2016 to Nov 2016 IT Administrator (Contract)

· Sole technician who provided technical support and systems administration to 100+ users in new office supporting executives, finance, marketing, and engineering departments

# DominoComp Technology Source

San Jose, CA · Sep 2014 to Jan 2016

IT Support Specialist

- Provided tier 1 and 2 software and hardware support locally and remotely to 100+ clients
- Reduced help desk calls by 30% by developing end-user training and knowledge database

# Citi's Sleepworld

IT & Customer Services Support

San Jose, CA · Jun 2011 to Sep 2014

- · Provided desktop support and trained 25 staffs the efficiently use of business systems and peripherals improving weekly shipments by double
- · Handled customer inquiries, billing concerns, service requests, and issued return merchandise authorizations

## Foothill-De Anza Community College District

Cupertino, CA · Aug 2009 to Jun 2011

IT Support Assistant